hello everyone it's me in my sweatpants
wearing my fuzzy socks
because i have one day left until i
start my internship
and i can just not be expected to put on
normal clothes that you play on the
street right now
so yeah sorry not sorry but today we're
going to do an unboxing of this
massive package because a few weeks ago
microsoft reached out to me yes you
heard that right
microsoft reached out to mwah um
i could not believe it either but
they said that they have a device that
could replace
the free devices which i currently use
because i currently use a macbook pro
a macbook and an ipad pro and i need all
three of them because all three of them
do different things and
there's not one apple device that does
all of it for me
um so they said they have something that
could do that and i said
okay show me and so they sent me this
this is a gift
um but i am not sponsored to say
anything positive
and today we're just gonna unbox it take
a look at what they actually sent me
and yeah let's do it okay so i already
had to open these parts of the box
because i have to hide my address
um but yeah let's go
oh wow there's like wood
like i don't know how to put it wait
oh my god i think this is like a wooden
box okay so here we go
there is this sort of box like thing
because
when you take out the plastic you can
see the it's a real box
um so i'm just gonna have to figure out
how oh oh okay it opens like this
so we do have to take it out in order to
open it
damn it's so heavy okay let me get this
out of the box then then i'll get back
to you
okay so we made it we have the box um i
gotta say this box has like really
like quite thick wood so like it's quite
heavy
like you can store stuff in here and
it's gonna stay safe
um so this is what it looks like um so
yeah let's open it up
this is so fancy um this is so cool like
it literally has like my name printed on
it i don't know if you guys can see this
well
and then it also has the microsoft thing
on it um so i now have proof
that i once got a gift from microsoft
which is still so insane to me to say
um but yeah let's take a look at what is
actually in here
um i'm guessing we open it up like this
we're gonna
take a look at this first and then we're
gonna take a look at this
i can already show you guys this what it
looks like
we're gonna take a look at that in a
moment
oh i did not realize it has the
microsoft logo in the wood um that's
cute
wow this is the most fancy gift i have
ever gotten
from any brand um so thank you
okay so this is how we open it
hello we're gonna have a satisfying
moment
oh it's stuck that was not so satisfying
there we go now let's go
oh wow hi
um so this is the microsoft surface book
free so that would be
this one right here um
looks pretty cool i think it looks
pretty you know very modern
um very different than my um pink
macbook
admittedly um but i like it
it's it's different but cool like i can
see myself like at uni with this
maybe with some cool peppy stickers on
here
um i have plans for this um i'm hoping
it's also you know just
gonna do a job of free devices which
would be amazing
it is a little heavier than my small
macbook
but i believe you can actually take off
the screen basically i'm making this
sound very weird
um the idea is you take up a screen and
you can use it like a tablet
so you don't always have to use it as a
laptop um
so i'm gonna figure out how to do that
in just a second
but this is so cool
oh my god and it has a very satisfying
click
i like that so yeah that's what it looks
like
and let's explore the rest in this
massive wooden box and then we're gonna
get back to this one
okay so we also got a cup which is so
cute because it has an e
on it and um well my name is elena so
that
fits very well um and they also gave us
some tea
which is cute breakfast blend also like
very color fitting
thanks this is this is such an you know
organized gift
um because everything in here is like
nicely blue
i'm i'm still like so in shock that i'm
unboxing a gift from microsoft that's
very surreal to me
um so yeah i'm
just a little hyped up right now okay
okay wait
what am i doing
can i take this out because i would love
to use this box
this oh whoa
there's something under this okay i was
like
i can like you know use this box now and
throw some of my stuff in it because you
better believe
i will never throw this box away like
ever
like you don't just get like a microsoft
box
out of freaking wood to throw it away um
but there's something under this um so i
don't know if this is just paper
um but let's take a look oh wow
oh my god we we got more gifts
okay um there's a little bit of
instructions of what to do first
that's good because like the last time i
owned a microsoft device
was in about like 2010 um so
i need help um but whoa we
we got more gifts
oh my gosh okay um
first of all headphones the microsoft
surface
headphones too okay the most important
thing has been settled about these
headphones
they are noise cancelling and that's
what i care about because
i'm an introvert who likes to block out
society and occasionally
isolate herself from mankind so
that's good they are also compatible
with the iphone which is important
because
in my day-to-day life i only use apple
devices
so i can still use this with my phone
which is great
um but yeah i'm excited to try them out
i was like
the color is just perfectly fitting the
um surface book that they gifted to me
which is
it's just cool you know i'm gonna roll
up a university
and i'm just gonna have everything
perfectly color-coded like
you wait for it okay and then we also
got
a pen um for um our surface book
because as i said you can take up a
screen i got this right
and i'm always very not confident when i
talk about tech because
i don't know enough about it to you know
be an expert and i know on youtube there
are a lot of tech youtubers
so i'm not coming for your brand because
i honestly couldn't i don't have the
knowledge to i'm just here being happy
that i've got an incredibly great gift
um so
give me my moment but don't expect tech
expertise from me
i can't even open this um
as i said i don't have expertise in tech
oh there's a sticker i'm hiding the
entire mess behind this box
but it's a mess um and i threw all the
plastic and stuff on the floor and it's
it's just not looking good um but that's
okay because
i got gifts and that's so cool and it's
not even my birthday
so hey um that's what the pen looks like
we're gonna give it a try um and see how
it works
what i did hear however is that they
actually have an eraser on top
um because i do use an apple pencil
um on my ipad pro and
it doesn't have an eraser on top and i
just think that's such a cool idea
because that's what you normally have
when you use
a normal pencil um so that's
pretty cool in my opinion but yeah and
then the last thing we have
oh my god i did see this um on their
website
i know what this is but i don't think i
would know what it is if i hadn't seen
it before because it just looks
very weird um it's a mouse
um but a very different mouse
pretty cool but like very random as well
as a mouse
oh my god these are so many gifts like
this is more than i get for my birthday
okay and christmas
and pretty much throughout the year um
so thank you
that's insane um i'm um
now first of all gonna find a place for
this amazing wooden box because
um it's mine and i shall cherish it
this is actually a really cool box like
this is such a treasure trove you know
like that's a flex i have my wooden box
with all my important things
okay i'm gonna stop talking about the
box um and we're gonna get to the
important part
which is the surface book so let's take
a look
several days later so it's been a few
days since i did the unboxing and i just
want to take some time so that i can
tell you about my initial experience
with the product
so yeah let's take a look at them and
let me tell you a little bit what i
think about them so far
first up is the microsoft surface book
free you guys already know what it looks
like but as you can see i also attached
my pen to it
because there is a quite strong magnet
on the tablet slash screen side of it
and you can just permanently store your
pen there it won't fall off if you put
it in your bag
and that's just super useful when you're
on the go especially
as a student now the other thing that
makes working with this device
just a little more convenient is that it
has something like face id on the iphone
and ipad
so basically you just open up your
device whenever you want to work with it
and you don't have to put in your pin
but instead you just take a look at the
lock screen
and you've unlocked your computer that
just makes it quicker to work with it i
found that to be like my favorite way of
unlocking it i don't think i've ever
put in my pin for this device so far
so it works really well with recognizing
your face you just have to sit in front
of it for
like a minute to set it up and then you
can always use it i was also right about
being able to detach the screen so you
just press this button right here
which is the button for just taking off
the screen and then the screen becomes a
little
loose and you can just take it off and
there you go now
as a tablet this thing also works quite
well
it is in my opinion a fully functioning
tablet but also a fully functioning
laptop
so it is really the best of both worlds
the tablet is
super super lightweight it is less heavy
than my ipad pro from 2017
which really surprised me because it is
bigger but yeah
i enjoy it so far i'm not the best
friend
of microsoft onenote yet i'm gonna see i
think i need to play around with the
settings a little bit
to customize it and you know just make
it a format that i like because i'm not
a big fan
of notes that can go off into nirvana
because
there so far i don't have a page but
rather just something you know that you
can keep writing on and on
and the document will just get bigger
for you but there are no page limits and
that's something that i personally don't
like um so i'm going to see
how to change it customize it or maybe
if there's a different note-taking app
that i like better on the surface
but other than that so far i can say the
screen quality is
amazing quality of pictures on the
screen is great
and the screen is very good at
recognizing the pen
and also it has great palm rejection so
that you know
when you rest your palm on it while
writing it won't think that that's also
something that you wanted to write um so
so far
really no complaints about the screen
the only thing that i just think
will take some getting used to is the
new system because it's different
than the mac system and i've had
macbooks for
a long time so i haven't really used a
microsoft device in a while
um but you can find your way around this
as an apple user
you kind of know where the important
things are but i think you know for
getting into the settings that you like
and just you know figuring out how to
use everything
finding the best apps i think that will
take a little bit of time
but so far i like it and i'm excited to
use it
now this thing over here isn't just a
keyboard it is also some extra battery
life for your tablet
so you can charge these two together if
you want and this one has
another few hours of battery life for
your tablet
so if you're running low you just put it
back into a keyboard and you can keep
using it
and actually i would recommend putting
it onto the keyboard even when you
want to take notes with your pen and
here's why because
this has a drawing position with the
keyboard
because you can also attach it the other
way around to the keyboard
basically you just put it on like this
and then you fold it and the cool thing
is now
you have an angled position and that's
actually better for writing than
writing on a straight flat surface
so this is actually more ergonomical so
i would recommend
using this when you're taking notes in a
lecture and i think it's just great that
they thought of this because
it means that you can keep your tablet
with a higher battery life while you're
taking notes
even when you don't want to use the
keyboard next up we have probably my
favorite thing which is
the mouse i just think it's so cool
because you can do this
and i can just see myself doing this all
the time
out of boredom um it's fun okay
now it is a mouse it does the job it has
its clicky thingies here
um i can't tell you yet how comfortable
this mouse is
for using it you know when you're
editing and stuff
so i will tell you about that in my long
term review
for now all i can say is the material is
super
soft and it's just really nice to touch
um
and it's just a really cool mouse
because i don't think anybody expects a
mouse to look like this
and i guess it's easy to transport
because it's very thin
but yeah that's really all i can say
about the mouse for now but i will give
you more details in my long term review
and lastly we have the headphones now
the headphones have already become a
part of my life i use them quite a bit
and i love them i think they're amazing
they have really great noise
cancellation
which is what an introverted person like
me really cares about
and i love their design because you can
turn on
both of these sides here to adjust both
the noise cancelling level
but also how loud the sound is playing
and that's just
really useful now you can also click on
them if you want the sound to stop for a
moment
and they also have a recognition for
when you're taking them off
so for example when you want to talk to
someone and you take off your headphones
for a moment
then they will stop playing whatever
they played and when you put them back
on they will go back to playing it
which is really great if you're watching
youtube videos or something because
when you lose a few seconds there
sometimes you don't really know what's
going on anymore um but yeah
these i can only highly recommend um the
material is great it's very soft on the
ear
um it doesn't press your ears to your
head
which is something that like some
headphones are just too harsh for me in
terms of the pressure they put on your
ear
and these are less soft in terms of the
pressure that i put on your ear
than the bose quiet comfort um i
have these as well um but it's not a big
pressure difference
and it's certainly not like when you
take them off of their world that
you would really feel anything of it
it's just something i realized like
after using the two interchangeably
that um there is a bit of a difference
but these are still very very
comfortable to wear
and i think they're very stylish because
they're so big let me just show you
um i have a tiny head um but i like this
like this
is a look and i think it's a pretty cool
look especially because they're color
matching all the other things
um i think it will just be a very
aesthetically pleasing look if i use all
of the devices together
um but yeah these i can highly recommend
especially adjusting both the noise
cancellation and
the sound level with these little wheels
means that it's more precise when you're
adjusting it and that's just a big plus
so yeah these headphones are a big yes
for me
and that's it for the quick close-ups
and my first impressions
now i hope you guys enjoyed this video
and i will be doing a long-term review
so
in about like a month or maybe a month
and a half i will get back to you guys
on how these devices have been holding
up and whether i think
that they are good devices to use as
main devices as a university student
yeah thank you so much for watching and
i can't believe
that i got a gift from microsoft but i'm
incredibly grateful
have a nice day bye
[Music]
you