hello everyone its Alena and I'm back
with another video and today I wanted to
talk to you guys about something rather
serious because unfortunately it has
happened to me more than once that
people have been stealing my content so
for those of you who don't know I'm not
just doing YouTube I also write a blog
and I've actually written this blog for
years before I started at YouTube and
there are share my pictures and I write
a few personal stories about my life or
you know things I like and pretty much
whatever is on my mind and then I also
do YouTube where I share my videos and
then I also have a second channel where
i share videos on law and then i also
have a second website about law and
there are just you know write about my
opinions on some legal topics luckily
nobody has ever stolen my writing or at
least I don't know about it but I think
that makes sense because it's pretty
personal so I don't think that anybody
would want to steal it but I have had
people steal some of my pictures and it
has also happened to me that somebody
stole a video of mine and that's why I
wanted to talk to you guys about that
today and I also wanted to explain to
people why you really shouldn't be
taking content creators work and using
it without crediting them or just taking
it and straight up uploading it on your
own profile that's absolutely not OK
and I know it comes in creatives often
say that but in this video I wanted to
show you guys why you're really
disrespecting any content creator if
you're stealing their work without
crediting them or you're just straight
up taking it and uploading it on your
own account taking away their ability to
make even a small profit from it on
their own account and I just want to
show you guys why that is really
problematic and why it is really not OK
so I'm gonna split this video into two
parts so first I'm going to talk about
pictures that I've had stolen from me
and then I'm gonna talk about the video
so yeah let's get into it
so as I already said I share pictures on
my blog but I also share pictures and it
for my thumbnails here on YouTube and I
also share pictures on my socials so as
you guys probably realized whenever you
watch a video of mine at the start there
is this little stripe here at the bottom
and it just says socials I have
and what my name on them is and I put
these socials out there into the public
and I know that thousands of people who
watch my videos can then you know search
me on these socials add me and look at
the pictures in the content that I put
out there and that's why these socials
are social
I keep very very filtered okay I really
think about what is the kind of content
that I want to put out there you know
what do I want to share with my audience
what do I want out there in the public
I don't ever watermark the pictures that
I put out there and I don't you know add
like a little add aleena hand trick in
these pictures because I just think it
really destroys the picture I don't
think it's pretty I want people to enjoy
the pictures as they are and you know
very often there is a lot of learning
involved in pictures that I make so like
here I want to show you guys just a few
examples of things that I've done on my
blog those are pictures you know that
take a lot of work they take creative
thinking about what am I going to do
with these pictures and then they take a
lot of work in to you know learning how
to edit them the correct way that they
end up looking the way they are and yes
you may just look at this picture for
like ten seconds maybe hit a like button
on Instagram and that's it but as a
content creator sometimes you put hours
of work into a single picture so if
someone just takes it and uses it or
even pretends that it's their own that
is really just disrespectful towards the
hours of work that you put into this
picture and I just quickly wanted to
give you guys an example of an Instagram
post that I've recently made just so you
guys can understand how much work goes
into a single picture that you guys
probably look at for 10 seconds but this
is how much were content creators put
into it okay so this is the post so for
this picture I actually had to think
about what kind of picture do I want to
take okay because I took us in my bad
now I'm the only person who works on my
channel and on my socials so I literally
take all of my pictures by myself so you
know I had to use a tripod then I had to
use my camera I had to connect my camera
into my phone so that I can then take my
picture by myself basically then I had
to go and edit this picture that I had
to think of a caption and then I could
put it out there and I had to schedule
it to make sure that it comes out at the
right time so let that caption then
would make sense
so all in a wall I have probably spent
about an hour to two hours on one
picture and this is just a picture on my
social this is not even a picture where
you know I have to be a lot more precise
with the editing because it's going to
be a lot bigger on my blog so people can
really see if the editing is bad but
this is just a picture for an Instagram
post
and this is one to two hours of work and
if people just take it and pretend that
there's you know that kind of sucks for
a content creator because you put the
work into it so that you know hopefully
the people who watch your content who
consume it enjoy it and you know I like
doing that and I have a lot of fun doing
it but it really sucks when people like
your work so much that they want to
share it but they don't respect your
work enough to give you credit or even
it first of all ask if they allowed to
share it and at this point you're
probably wondering so what exactly
happened with your pictures that you're
so mad so what happened with my pictures
and people stealing them is that people
started using them on different apps and
pretend that they're me basically um so
I have people message me and be like hey
we messaged on this in this dating app
is it cool if we continue talking here
on Instagram and I'm like who are you
what is this app I have never even heard
of it and um that is something that's
just not cool okay first of all if you
are stealing my picture and you're using
it on a dating app and then somebody
messages review they are thinking that
their messaging or a person that looks
like me and you know nowadays most
people know how to do a reverse image
search on Google okay for those of you
guys don't know a reverse image search
is a search for a picture so you can
take a picture from your laptop and tell
Google search for this picture on the
internet and I am a very searchable
person okay I am NOT a big content
creator I'm not a celebrity at all but I
have a blog that has been written for
years there are a lot of pictures of me
on the Internet that are public and so
you can really easily find out who I am
if you have a picture of me and so it's
no wonder that if you use pictures that
I used on my blog or on my public
socials that these people who didn't
message review find me on my actual
socials so you know you are hurting them
because they think they are messaging
with me and you know maybe they read
about my personality my blog or whatever
and they think oh really great I really
want
you know get to know this person but
actually they are not messaging with me
and I also don't know what you're
getting out of it because if you ever
done meet with these people in real life
you're not gonna look like me okay I
don't have a twin so I don't understand
why you would do that you're hurting
yourself because you are not actually
telling them who you really are and you
are hurting other people by pretending
to be someone you're not
and it's really not okay and you know I
never thought that this would happen to
someone like me because I'm a very small
content creator here on YouTube and I
have a blog and yes a couple of thousand
people read it a month but honestly it
down it's a very small audience in the
internet nowadays and you know I talk
about pretty uncontroversial topics like
you know university related things every
once in a while on my blog and maybe
talk about a beauty product that I like
about that's pretty much it so I never
really thought that people will be
stealing my pictures or you know any
content that I put out there because I'm
just not that big as a content creator
and I know that I look pretty average so
I just never thought that people would
want to steal my pictures from my
Instagram and then use it on things like
dating websites but unfortunately this
is something that has happened to me and
I wanted to address it here just to let
you guys know that if you have one of
these people who did it please stop
doing it because every time you do it I
then have to be the person to tell
someone
no this isn't me and it sucks for me to
have to do that because I know that I'm
probably hurting this person who sent me
a message and you know maybe was really
excited to meet somebody new and the
other thing is I don't have to go on an
internet search find out how to contact
this dating website and then I'm going
to figure out how to get this profile
taken down with their customer support
and you know it has happened to me that
somebody messaged me and they were
referring to a dating website which i
think is pretty shady I'm not gonna give
this website more publicity by promoting
it on my channel this is not what my
channel is about but you know I don't
have to go and deal with like shady web
sites and whatever in order to get these
profiles taken down because obviously a
I don't want more people thinking I'm on
there and B I don't want you
use my pictures and pretend to be me and
you know then you just take another hour
or two hours of my work because I have
to go
email them prove to them that I am the
actual person and you know that's a lot
of work proving to somebody that you are
actually the content creator so that's
why you know that I have to go and
explain be like see I'm emailing you
from the right email address this is the
email address which is linked to my
YouTube account you can see it here on
my YouTube account
blah blah blah you know I have to go on
and on and on explaining and proving to
them that I am me and that is just a lot
of work it's absolutely unnecessary work
and you are the reason that I have to do
this work and it's not cool okay it's
just not okay I am really mad about this
at this point because it hasn't been
just one time and that is why I'm not
okay with it and that is why I'm making
this video and I'm really sorry for this
negative content but I just think it had
to be out there and I hope that you guys
now understand that you may just see a
picture that is really easy to just take
from my socials and put on your own
profile but I hope you can understand
that I put a lot of work into any
content I put out there and that I also
then have to put in a lot of work to get
your fake profiles taken down and that
is just not fair to me okay I'm a
university student I have better things
to do than email some weird dating
websites and be like hi I'm actually me
but I'm not on your dating web site
please take my profile down okay
that is not how I want to spend my
afternoons so please don't make me spend
him like that okay so now that we've
been through my rant about people
stealing my pictures and pretending to
be me let's get into people stealing my
work here on YouTube so what has
happened to me is that somebody took my
video uploaded it in the same length and
you know just the entire video on their
own account somewhere else and posted it
and that is not okay now I am aware if
you are allowed to use content from
other creators if you use it for
commentary for parody or for anything
like that but that is not what happened
here at all the passengers took the
entire video and uploaded it
on their own account on a different
video sharing website and that's really
not okay and I want to explain to you
guys why so before we get into it this
is the video that was stolen and where
it was uploaded and this is a Chinese
website and in all honesty my Chinese is
pretty horrible so I don't know how to
get it taken down if you guys have had
any experience with this please let me
know because I really do want to get it
out of there because it doesn't belong
there now before somebody finds out in
the comments yes I am aware that YouTube
is blocked in China and it you can only
access it using a VPN connection and if
somebody was lived in Hong Kong for two
years and who has many friends in a
Chinese mainland I do understand there
are a lot of people who want to share
content that is available to students
around the world with Chinese students
because many of them just can't access
it because they're in China and YouTube
and average services are blocked there I
fully understand that but if you are
somebody like that and you think that
the content of one creator is so good
that Chinese students should have access
to it as well then why are you not
respecting the content creator enough to
ask them for permission I am somebody
who has a connection to China I'm
somebody really understand that problem
so why don't you send me a message and
simply ask for permission under every
video of mine the contact section of my
blog is linked in the info box all my
socials are linked under my videos you
can always drop me a message there and
be like hey I want to do that Matt
could I please share it but if you don't
ask the answer is always no okay and if
you ask and I say no then it's a no then
you don't have permission to go steal my
video and upload it somewhere else you
simply don't have permission you don't
own the content you haven't put hours of
work into this content so it's not yours
so don't take it and there's also
financial aspect to this because you are
basically stealing my money if you take
my work and you upload it somewhere else
and I don't get paid for that so the
thing is whenever you click on my
YouTube video there's usually an ad
that's playing in a video and the reason
for that is that I'm a member of the
YouTube Partner Program so I get a
little
of money every time these ads play but
the thing is that is not a lot so I am
NOT here and saying you know I'm doing
YouTube for the money I'm really not but
the thing is there is a lot of costs
that are associated with having your
channel and you know having this little
revenue from ads just helps me to
finance this channel because it's really
not that easy if you're a university
student and I just quickly wanted to
give you guys a short outline of how
many things I actually have to pay for
as a content creator okay so I have a
tripod that is something that I bought
with my own money I have a video camera
which are also bought with my own money
I have a MacBook Pro which I use for
editing which are also paid for with my
own money and then I always have to pay
for my editing software then I also have
to pay for my photo editing software
because those thumbnails aren't creating
themselves and then I also have to pay
for licenses for the fonts that I'm
using in my thumbnails because other
people created these funds and I respect
their work enough to pay for it so why
aren't you respecting my work enough to
allow me to make a few cents from it in
order to then keep financing my work and
keep doing this if you think my content
is great thank you so much but please
respect me and have as a content creator
to not steal it because that's really
not cool you know I'm really not doing
YouTube for the money because all the
things that I just told you about that
I've paid for with my own money
those are thousands and thousands of
dollars okay I mean everybody knows how
much MacBooks are nowadays and all these
things you can probably guess that I've
spent at least three thousand dollars
just on being able to make this channel
and that is a lot of money and in all
honesty I haven't made something that's
even close to that from YouTube since I
started monetizing my videos and that's
absolutely okay because I'm not doing
this for the money but you know just
having a bit of money that comes back
from these videos it really helps me as
a content creator to keep making them
because I have a very limited financial
ability and I'm a student so you know
there is not much money that I can spend
on this channel but I nonetheless made
it possible and you know that was
already a lot of work just to be able to
buy these things I had to work in order
to
have this money to then start this
channel and I don't regret doing that
not tool you know I would do it all
again because I really love making
videos I really enjoy interacting with
you guys but you know if you didn't take
my video and steal it it just makes me
upset and then I don't have fun doing
this anymore and I just think it's very
disrespectful towards any content
creator if you steal their work and just
straight-up upload it somewhere else and
yes this person did then you know link
everything that I had linked in my
infobox but that is not enough you
cannot just take somebody's content not
use it for commentary or anything just
upload it somewhere else without the
monetization that these people are
actually entitled to with their videos
and just be like well I mean I gave them
credit but I actually stole their source
of income by doing so thank you so much
for crediting me it is not helping and
if the person who has uploaded it on
this Chinese website is watching this
please take this video down it's
absolutely disgusting to steal
somebody's work without permission and
thereby take away their source of income
which they need in order to pay for
creating this content it's not ok and if
you are somebody who wants to make my
videos more accessible please message me
tell me about your ideas tell me where
you want to share it what your audience
is if you already have an audience there
let me know and I make an informed
decision do what I want you to be able
to share these videos or not I have had
people reach out to me via my blog and
ask hey there is a post that I really
want to share in China but I know that I
can't share this video there would it be
okay if I shared it really chat or
something else and you know then I think
about it you know I decide is it worth
it is it not do I want to take this risk
yes or no and if I say yes then it's a
green light go ahead if it's a no it's a
note and then don't use my work because
it's my work I've put hours of work into
creating a concept writing outlines
filming it editing it creating a
thumbnail creating the text on the info
box and then posting it and promoting it
on my socials so you taking it away just
like that it's not cool
so please don't do it please don't do it
to any content creator and I hope that
this video just helped you guys
understand why content creators get so
emotional when people steal their work
because we put a lot of work into it
even me as a very very small content
creator of only a few thousand
subscribers even I put a lot of work
into it and you know you may not always
see that you know you just watch a ten
minute video and then you move on but
please remember everybody who puts
videos out there puts hours of work into
it so you know respect everybody who
does this work for you enough to just
credit their work and if you are sharing
it somewhere and it's actually monetized
on another platform ask the content
creator if you're allowed to do so and
if they say no please respect him enough
to take their no for what it is and no